Register of the Tadeusz Podgórski papers, 1952-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1952-1986
  - Polska Partia Socjalistyczna file, 1965-1986
    - Soboniewski, Stefan, 1974-1982 (Text 5: 74)
    - Solski, Kazimierz, 1974 (Text 5: 75)
    - Sowinski, Kazimierz, 1973-1975 (Text 5: 76)
    - Sowula, Grzegorz, 1984 (Text 5: 77)
    - Spieczynski, T., 1981 (Text 5: 78)
    - Sporon, Henryk, 1983 (Text 5: 79)
    - Spyra, Andrzej, 1984-1985 (Text 5: 80)
    - Staszek, Aleksander, 1981-1984 (Text 5: 81)
    - Stran, Jerzy, 1981-1982 (Text 5: 82)
    - Stroynowski, Juliusz, 1974-1982 (Text 5: 83)
    - Strzelecki, Waldemar, circa 1980 (Text 5: 84)
    - Studzinski, Jerzy, 1981-1982 (Text 5: 85)
    - Stypulowski, Andrzej, 1976 (Text 6: 1)
    - Sukiennicka, Halina, 1982 (Text 6: 2)
    - Sukniewicz, Andrzej, 1976 (Text 6: 3)
    - Sulecki, Wladyslaw, 1981-1985 (Text 6: 4)
    - Sulik, Boleslaw, 1979 (Text 6: 5)
    - Sulkowski, Witold, 1983 (Text 6: 6)
    - Sumirski, Slawomir, 1985 (Text 6: 7)
    - Szacki, Wiktor, 1974 (Text 6: 8)
    - Szadkowski, Zygmunt, 1982-1985 (Text 6: 9)
    - Szafranski, Zbigniew, 1981 (Text 6: 10)
    - Szczepanski, Michal, 1982 (Text 6: 11)
    - Szczerbicki, Stanislaw, circa 1980 (Text 6: 12)
    - Sznarbachowski, Wlodzimierz, 1977-1985 (Text 6: 13)
    - Szponder, Jan, 1978 (Text 6: 14)
    - Szott, Leon, 1973-1974 (Text 6: 15)
    - Szulczynski, Leon, 1975 (Text 6: 16)
    - Szulkin, Ryszard, 1982 (Text 6: 17)
    - Szumski, Mikolaj, 1982-1986 (Text 6: 18)
    - Szymkowska, Irena, 1974-1978 (Text 6: 19)
    - Szymula, Jerzy, 1979 (Text 6: 20)
    - Szymura, B., 1975 (Text 6: 21)
    - Sledz-Jedrzejczyk, Elzbieta, 1984 (Text 6: 22)
    - Swiecicki, Jakub, 1977 (Text 6: 23)
    - Talarczyk, Mieczyslaw, 1985 (Text 6: 24)
    - Taranowski, Czeslaw, 1974 (Text 6: 25)
    - Tarwid-Nowak, Anna, 1983 (Text 6: 26)
    - Tendyra, Dzidka, 1986 (Text 6: 27)
    - Thomas, Stephen, 1977 (Text 6: 28)
    - Tiplt, Alexander, 1984-1986 (Text 6: 29)
    - Tobolik, Jan, 1974 (Text 6: 30)
    - Tomaszewski, Marian, 1965 (Text 6: 31)
    - Topolewski, Wojciech, 1982 (Text 6: 32)
    - Toskova, Ruth, 1985 (Text 6: 33)
    - Trzeciak, Czeslaw, 1985 (Text 6: 34)
    - Turowski, Mieczyslaw, 1984 (Text 6: 35)
    - Turzynski, Tadeusz, 1986 (Text 6: 36)
    - Tykierka, Tomasz, 1986 (Text 6: 37)
    - Urbanowicz, Janusz, 1985 (Text 6: 38)
    - Urbanski, Alfred, 1973-1978 (Text 6: 39)
    - Uschakow, 1983 (Text 6: 40)
    - Wajdlejt, Helena, 1984 (Text 6: 41)
    - Wantula, W., 1978 (Text 6: 42)
    - Wasik, Slawomir, 1986 (Text 6: 43)
    - Wasiluk, M., 1974 (Text 6: 44)
    - Wawrzyniak, Wieslaw, 1977-1986 (Text 6: 45)
    - Wasalski, Feliks, 1986 (Text 6: 46)
    - Wasik, Stanislaw, 1974-1985 (Text 6: 47)
    - Wendorff, Bohdan, 1986 (Text 6: 48)
    - Wesolowska, Cecylia, 1984 (Text 6: 49)
    - Wieczorek, Jacek, 1984-1986 (Text 6: 50)
    - Wieczorek, Ryszard, 1981-1986 (Text 6: 51)
    - Wierzbianski, Boleslaw, 1985-1986 (Text 6: 52)
    - Wierzbowski, Marek, 1982-1986 (Text 6: 53)
    - Wieckowski, Andrzej, 1983-1985 (Text 6: 54)
    - Wildstein, Bronislaw, 1982 (Text 6: 55)
    - Wilk, Franciszek, 1971-1986 (Text 6: 56)
    - Winiarski, Lukasz, 1972-1975 (Text 6: 57)
    - Wirpsza, Witold, 1973-1978 (Text 6: 58)
    - Wiszowaty, Zygmunt, 1981 (Text 6: 59)
    - Wisniewski, Edmund, 1977-1986 (Text 6: 60)
    - Wisniewski, Miroslaw, 1982-1984 (Text 6: 61)
    - Witkowski, Julian, 1974-1986 (Text 6: 62)
    - Wlodarczyk, Waldemar, 1982-1986 (Text 6: 63)
    - Wojciechowski, Józef, 1972-1975 (Text 6: 64)
    - Wojciechowski, Marek, 1984 (Text 6: 65)
    - Wos, Jerzy, 1977 (Text 6: 66)
    - Wosik, Jerzy, 1984-1986 (Text 6: 67)
    - Wosinski, Ryszard, 1981-1984 (Text 6: 68)
    - Wójcik, Zdzislaw, 1981 (Text 6: 69)
    - Wysocka, J., 1985 (Text 6: 70)
    - Wyzga, Ryszard, 1984 (Text 6: 71)
    - Zaborowski, Wojciech, 1982 (Text 6: 72)
    - Zagórski, Waclaw, 1975-1983 (Text 6: 73)
    - Zajac, Aleksander, 1982 (Text 6: 74)
    - Zakrzewski, Ryszard, 1975-1982 (Text 6: 75)
    - Zaleski, Jerzy, 1978-1986 (Text 6: 76)
    - Zalewski, Olgierd, 1977 (Text 6: 77)
    - Zaluski, Jerzy, 1982 (Text 6: 78)
    - Zarzewski, Stanislaw, 1965-1969 (Text 6: 79)
    - Zarzycka, Ewa, 1974-1975 (Text 6: 80)
    - Zawadzki, Janusz, 1966-1978 (Text 6: 81)
    - Zawadzki, Tadeusz, 1972-1981 (Text 7: 1)
    - Zbiegniewski, 1985 (Text 7: 2)
    - Zielkiewicz, Jacek, 1986 (Text 7: 3)
    - Zieba, Andrzej, 1982-1985 (Text 7: 4)
    - Zimmer, Szczepan K., 1975 (Text 7: 5)
    - Ziola, Stefan, 1977 (Text 7: 6)
    - Ziólkowska, Lidia, 1985 (Text 7: 7)
    - Zwierzchowski, Tomasz, 1986 (Text 7: 8)
    - Zaba, Jaroslaw, 1982 (Text 7: 9)
    - Zaba, Norbert, 1984-1985 (Text 7: 10)
    - Zegadlo, Henryk, 1982 (Text 7: 11)
    - Zenczykowski, T., 1976 (Text 7: 12)
    - Zmigrodzki, Józef, 1972-1984 (Text 7: 13)
    - Zurek, Bogdan, 1982-1986 (Text 7: 14)
    - Unidentified, 1965-1986 (Text 7: 15)
  - Radio Free Europe file, 1952-1986
    The correspondence in this section is of professional nature between Podgórski and his colleagues at Radio Free Europe, most notably: Jan Nowak Jezioranski and Zdzislaw Najder. Some of the letters are from private individuals who listened to Podgórski’s broadcasts and decided to write their opinion and comments.
    - Basista, Mieczyslaw, 1973-1975 (Text 7: 16)
    - Blaszczynski, Jerzy, 1981 (Text 7: 17)
    - Bobrowski, Slawomir, 1977-1985 (Text 7: 18)
    - Borucki, Marek, 1983-1984 (Text 7: 19)
    - Ciesielczyk, Marek, 1981 (Text 7: 20)
    - Dziechciowski, Slawomir, 1983-1986 (Text 7: 21)
    - Erling, S. C., 1980 (Text 7: 22)
    - Frydryszak, Hanna, 1984 (Text 7: 23)
    - Gaik, T., 1970-1983 (Text 7: 24)
    - Gapczynski, Józef, 1983-1985 (Text 7: 25)
    - Glebowski, Ryszard, 1984 (Text 7: 26)
    - Gross, Feliks, 1977-1983 (Text 7: 27)
    - Hora, Vaclav, 1977 (Text 7: 28)
    - Isalski, Michal, 1981 (Text 7: 29)
    - Jalowiecki, Stanislaw, 1983-1984 (Text 7: 30)
    - Jurszczak, Marek, 1985 (Text 7: 31)
    - Kenic, Janusz, 1983 (Text 7: 32)
    - Kielsa, Mieczyslaw, 1974-1982 (Text 7: 33)
    - Koczerska, Teresa, 1986-1988 (Text 7: 34)
    - Kostecki, Andrzej, circa 1980 (Text 7: 35)
    - Kotlarski, Ignacy Icchak, 1986 (Text 7: 36)
    - Kowalczyk, Czeslaw, 1981 (Text 7: 37)
    - Krókicki, H., 1980-1984 (Text 7: 38)
    - Krzyzanowski, J., 1985 (Text 7: 39)
    - Lodynski, Andrzej, 1982 (Text 7: 40)
    - Michalowski, Z., 1981 (Text 7: 41)
    - Mozdzierz, Ryszard, 1982-1985 (Text 7: 42)
    - Myszkowski, Hieronim, 1984 (Text 7: 43)
    - Najder, Zdzislaw, 1982-1986 (Text 7: 44)
    - Niezgoda, S., 1983 (Text 7: 45)
    - Nowak, Barbara i Tadeusz, 1982 (Text 7: 46)
    - Nowak, Czeslaw, 1984 (Text 7: 47)
    - Nowak-Jezioranski, Jan, 1984-1986 (Text 7: 48)
    - Nugustyniak, Ewa, 1982 (Text 7: 49)
    - Olszewski, Swiatopelk, 1972-1981 (Text 7: 50)
    - Pietrzak, Tadeusz, 1984 (Text 7: 51)
    - Podgórski, Danuta, 1974-1975 (Text 7: 52)
    - Podgórski, Leslaw, 1982 (Text 7: 53)
    - Pokucinski, Jerzy, 1982 (Text 7: 54)
    - Ptaczek, Józef, 1986 (Text 7: 55)
    - Raina, Peter, 1977 (Text 7: 56)
    - Rek, Jerzy, 1982 (Text 7: 57)
    - Rokicki, Wiktor, 1974-1979 (Text 7: 58)
    - Romiszewscy, Jolanta i Przemyslaw, 1982 (Text 7: 59)
    - Ruchniewicz, Iwona, 1982 (Text 7: 60)
    - Run, Ana, 1977 (Text 7: 61)
    - Rymszewicz, Zygmunt, 1981-1982 (Text 7: 62)
    - Strauss, Franz Josef, 1985 (Text 7: 63)
    - Szenajch, Aleksander, 1974-1981 (Text 7: 64)
    - Sliwanski, Jan, 1977 (Text 7: 65)
    - Tarwid-Nowak, Anna, 1983 (Text 7: 66)
    - Tomula, Wieslaw, 1978 (Text 7: 67)
    - Urban, George, 1986 (Text 7: 68)
    - Urbanowicz, Janusz, 1982-1984 (Text 7: 69)
    - Witon, Krzysztof, 1982 (Text 7: 70)
    - Wojnarski, Tadeusz, 1986 (Text 7: 71)
    - Wójcik, Witold, 1981-1982 (Text 7: 72)
    - Unidentified, 1952-1985 (Text 7: 73)
- Emigre Affairs file, 1952-1986
  Comprised of administrative records, printed matter, and documents from the Polish Émigré Union in Germany. Section documents Polish émigré activities in Germany and Podgórski’s involvement in their efforts.
  - Administrative Records, 1952-1986 (Text 7: 74)
  - Printed Matter, 1984-1986 (Text 8: 1)
  - Zjednoczenie Polskich Uchodzców w Niemczech, 1975-1985 (Text 8: 2)
- Polska Partia Socjalistyczna file, 1952-1986
  Various documents outlining the efforts and activities of the Polska Partia Socjalistyczna. Includes administrative records, articles, communiqués, circulars, conference materials, photographs, publications and pamphlets created and distributed by the party.
  - Administrative Records, 1967-1985 (Text 8: 3)
  - Apele, 1981-1982 (Text 8: 4)
  - Application Materials, circa 1970 (Text 8: 5)
  - Articles, 1952-1986 (Text 8: 6)
  - Conferences, 1982-1983 (Text 8: 7)
  - Daszynski, Ignacy, 1981 (Text 8: 8)
  - Event Announcements, 1981-1985 (Text 8: 9)
  - German Language Materials, 1982-1985 (Text 8: 10)
  - Informacja, 1982-1985 (Text 8: 11)
  - "Informator", 1985 (Text 8: 12)
  - Instytut Polski i Muzeum Im. Gen. Sikorskiego, 1968, 1985 (Text 8: 13)
  - Komunikaty, 1983 (Text 8: 14)
  - Listy Otwarte, 1982-1985 (Text 8: 15)
  - Meetings, 1973-1986 (Text 8: 16)
  - Members and Addresses, 1986 (Text 9: 1)
  - Notatki, 1952-1986 (Text 9: 2)
  - Okólniki, 1976-1986 (Text 9: 3)
  - Oswiadczenia, 1980-1986 (Text 9: 4)
  - P. P. S. Writings, 1977-1986 (Text 9: 5)
  - Photographs, 1970-1986 (Text 9: 6-7)
  - "Polish Affairs - A Quarterly", 1981-1982 (Text 9: 8)
  - "Pravo Lidu", 1982 (Text 9: 9)
  - Presseerklarung, 1981-1983 (Text 9: 10)
  - "Program P. P. S. i Zadania P. P. S. na Obczyznie", 1978 (Text 9: 11)
  - Protokoly, 1984 (Text 9: 12)
  - "Przemiany", 1974-1985 (Text 10: 1-10)
  - "Przemiany" Administrative Records, 1982-1985 (Text 10: 11)
  - Receipts, 1971-1986 (Text 11: 1)
  - "Robotnik", 1967-1982 (Text 11: 2)
  - "Rodak", 1974-1983 (Text 11: 3)
  - "Rzeczpospolita Polska", 1982-1986 (Text 11: 4)
  - Solidarnosc, 1982-1985 (Text 11: 5)
  - Sprawozdania, 1983-1985 (Text 11: 6)
  - Sprawy, 1981 (Text 11: 7)
  - Statement of Principels of the Polish Socialist Party, 1984 (Text 11: 8)
  - Uchwaly, 1979-1983 (Text 11: 9)
  - "Wypadki Czerwcowe i Dzialalnosc Komitetu Obrony Robotników", 1977 (Text 11: 10)
  - Z kroniki P. P. S., circa 1980 (Text 11: 11)
  - "Zasadnicze Uchwaly i Wyniki VII Zjazdu Polskiej Partii Socjalistycznej na Obczyznie", 1978 (Text 11: 12)
  - Zawiadomienia, 1982-1983 (Text 11: 13)
  - Zegadlo, Henryk, circa 1980 (Text 11: 14)
  - "Zew", 1972-1976 (Text 11: 15)
  - 90th Anniversary, 1982 (Text 11: 16)
- Radio Free Europe file, 1973-1982
  Comprised of various administrative documents, broadcasts, notes, and printed matter documenting the activities of Radio Free Europe, particularly the labor section, in Munich while under the direction of Podgórski.
  - Administrative Records, 1976-1982 (Text 11: 17)
  - Broadcasts, 1976-1982 (Text 11: 18)
  - Notatki, circa 1980 (Text 11: 19)
  - Printed Matter, 1973-1983 (Text 11: 20)
- Writings, 1952-1986
  Scope and Cotents
  Consists of various writings of Podgórski as well as the writings of other activists. The section also includes various articles that were gathered as research materials to produce some of the writings. Notable authors whose works appear in the section include: Adam Ciolkosz and Alicja Pomian-Pozerska Matulewicz.
  - Authorship Unknown, circa 1980 (Text 11: 21)
  - Bogacz, Ryszard, circa 1980 (Text 11: 22)
  - Chilecki, Andrzej, 1986 (Text 11: 23)
  - Ciolkosz, Adam, 1975 (Text 11: 24)
  - Ciolkosz and Magiera, circa 1970 (Text 11: 25)
  - Dziechciowski, Tadeusz, circa 1980 (Text 11: 26)
  - Inicjatywa Wydawnicza Aspekt, 1984 (Text 12: 1)
  - Jalinski, B. J., circa 1980 (Text 12: 2)
  - Jalowiecki, Stanislaw, 1984 (Text 12: 3)
  - Konarski, Feliks, 1983 (Text 12: 4)
  - Pomian-Pozerska Matulewicz, Alicja, 1984 (Text 12: 5)
  - Majchrzyk, Eugeniusz, 1984 (Text 12: 6)
  - M. M., circa 1980 (Text 12: 7)
  - Mozdzierz, Ryszard, 1981 (Text 12: 8)
  - Nowak, Leszek, 1981 (Text 12: 9)
  - Podgórski, Tadeusz, 1952-1986 (Text 12: 10)
  - Podlaski, Kazimierz, 1984 (Text 12: 11)
  - Szulkin, Lucjan, 1980 (Text 12: 12)
  - T. J., circa 1980 (Text 12: 13)
  - Wilk, Maciej, circa 1980 (Text 12: 14)
  - Witkowski, Julian, 1982 (Text 12: 15)